When I first arrived in beautiful Zimbabwe,
عندما وصلت أول مرة الى زيمبابوي الجميلة
it was difficult to understand that 35 percent of the population
كان صعباً فهم أن 35 بالمائة من سكانها
is HIV positive.
مصابون بمرض الإيدز
It really wasn't until I was invited to the homes of people
كان صعباً حتى دُعيت لمنازل الناس
that I started to understand the human toll of the epidemic.
عندها بدأت أفهم الخسائر البشرية لهذا الوباء
For instance, this is Herbert with his grandmother.
على سبيل المثال، هذا هاربرت مع جدته
When I first met him, he was sitting on his grandmother's lap.
عندما إلتقيتهم في البداية، كان يجلس في حضن جدته
He has been orphaned, as both of his parents died of AIDS,
كان يتيماً، حيث مات والديه بسبب مرض الإيدز
and his grandmother took care of him until he too died of AIDS.
وأعتنت به جدته حتى مات هو أيضاً بسبب الإيدز
He liked to sit on her lap
كان يحب الجلوس البقاء في حضنها
because he said that it was painful for him to lie in his own bed.
لأنه قال أنه مؤلم بالنسبة له الإستلقاء على فراشه
When she got up to make tea, she placed him in my own lap
عندما قامت جدته لصنع الشاي، وضعته في حضني
and I had never felt a child that was that emaciated.
ولم أشعر قط بطفل في مثل هذا الهزال
Before I left, I actually asked him if I could get him something.
قبل أن أغادر، سألته اذا ما كان يريد شيئاً
I thought he would ask for a toy, or candy,
حسبت أنه سيطلب دُمية، أو حلوى
and he asked me for slippers,
لكنه طلب نعالاً
because he said that his feet were cold.
لأنه قال أن قدميه كانت باردة
This is Joyce who's -- in this picture -- 21.
هذه جويس التي-- في هذه الصورة-- 21
Single mother, HIV positive.
أم وحيدة، مصابة بالإيدز
I photographed her before and after
صورتها قبل وبعد
the birth of her beautiful baby girl, Issa.
ميلاد طفلتها الجميلة، إيسا
And I was last week walking on Lafayette Street in Manhattan
وكنت أتجول في الاسبوع الماضي في شارع لافياتي في مانهاتن
and got a call from a woman who I didn't know,
وتلقيت إتصال من أمرأة لا أعرفها
but she called to tell me that Joyce had passed away
لكنها اتصلت لتخبرني بأن جويس قد ماتت
at the age of 23.
عن عمر ال23
Joyce's mother is now taking care of her daughter,
وتعتني والدة جويس الآن بطفلتها
like so many other Zimbabwean children
مثل الكثير من الأطفال الزيمبابويين الآخرين
who've been orphaned by the epidemic.
الذين تيتموا بسبب الوباء
So a few of the stories.
وهذه القليل من القصص
With every picture,
لكن مع أي صورة
there are individuals who have full lives
هناك أفراد لديهم حياة كاملة
and stories that deserve to be told.
وقصص تستحق أن تحكى
All these pictures are from Zimbabwe.
كل هذه الصور من زيمبابوي
Chris Anderson: Kirsten, will you just take one minute,
كريس أندرسون: كرستين، فقط خلال دقيقة واحدة
just to tell your own story of how you got to Africa?
لتخبرينا قصتك عن كيف وصلتي الى إفريقيا
Kirsten Ashburn: Mmm, gosh.
كرستين أشبورن: ممم، يا إلهي
CA: Just --
ك أ: فقط--
KA: Actually, I was working at the time, doing production
ك أ: حسناً، في ذلك الوقت كنت أعمل، في إنتاج
for a fashion photographer.
لأجل تصوير الموضة
And I was constantly reading the New York Times,
وأقرأ النيويورك تايمز بإستمرار
and stunned by the statistics, the numbers.
وذهلت بالإحصائيات، الأرقام
It was just frightening.
كانت مخيفة جداً
So I quit my job
لذا تركت عملي
and decided that that's the subject that I wanted to tackle.
وقررت أن هذه هي القضية التي أريد معالجتها
And I first actually went to Botswana, where I spent a month --
وفي الواقع ذهبت الى بوتسوانا أولاً حيث قضيت شهراً--
this is in December 2000 --
كان هذا في ديسمبر عام 2000--
then went to Zimbabwe for a month and a half,
وبعدها ذهبت الى زيمبابوي لشهر ونصف
and then went back again this March 2002
ورجعت هناك مجدداً في مارس 2002
for another month and a half in Zimbabwe.
لشهر ونصف مجدداً في زيمبابوي
CA: That's an amazing story, thank you.
ك أ: هذه حكاية مذهلة، شكراً لك
KB: Thanks for letting me show these.
ك ب: شكراً لإتاحتك لي الفرصة للعرض --